Bharathi Kannan V

Full Stack Developer

Excellent in developing applications from given business requirements and efficient in maintaining existing software.

bharathikannanv05@gmail.com

www.bharathikannan.com

+919443470347

Coimbatore, India



WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Twilio 🗷

10/2022 - Present

Bangalore

Roles and Responsibilities

 Develop and maintain reusable react components for a Low Code Tool called Studio.

Technical Lead IV

Photon Infotech 🗷

05/2020 - 10/2022

Chennai

Roles and Responsibities

- Application lead managing a team of 2 Frontend engineers and 3 QA resources.
- Architect Lead to analyse and develop POCs for upcoming features in product.
- Full-stack developer with a primary focus on UI development.
- Implementing various coding patterns to tackle agile business requirements.

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions &

04/2016 - 11/2019

Coimbatore

Roles and Responsibilities

 Requirements Analysis, Design, Implementation, Development and Testing of .Net Web application

PROJECTS

Clinical Trials Web Application (05/2021 - Present)

- React web application used for Clinical trials to conduct studies on new drugs, which is primarily used by the hospital or site staff to study drug data on patients.
- Involves creating and using clinical forms to get data from patients, which involves complex calculations and branching logic.
- Patient data management, scheduling visits, visualizing data submitted by the patients on clinical forms.

ASP.NET MVC Web Application (11/2017 - 05/2018)

- This Web Application is developed for business users, who use it as an interactive tool to effectively manage the business data as well as user data.
- Features: Spreadsheet Export from the visualized data grid, Excel Upload, Displaying the uploaded excel on the web page, and providing the user an option to edit the spreadsheet.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College

2012 - 2016 Coimbatore

Specialization

 Computer Science and Engineering

SKILLS

React JS GraphQL AWS Amplify TypeScript

JavaScript Next JS AWS DynamoDB

Firebase Node JS C#

ACHIEVEMENTS

Epic React Certification from Kent C. Dodds (03/2021)

Workshop-based advanced React course provided by Kent C. Dodds and egghead.io. Learned about all the parts in web development with React from developing, styling, testing, and measuring the performance of a production application.

Front-End Web Development with React (03/2020)

Completed the course with 100% Grade provided by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology through Coursera

Certified Full Stack Engineer (03/2019)

Provided by National Institute of Information Technology and Sponsored by Cognizant Technology Solutions

Pick of the Month (10/2019)

In the Quarterly Newsletter for the proposal and development of Value add for the web application, which significantly saves \$43,000 US dollars for the client per year

First Prize in Android Hackathon 2k15 (11/2015)

Conducted by HR Cube at Jansons Institute of Technology, Coimbatore, and awarded with Part-Time Internship at HR Cube, a US-based IT company.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

An overall experience of 6+ years in Web Application Development, UI Design, Data modeling, and Web-based technologies (04/2016 - Present)

3 years of experience in SPA development with TypeScript, React, Redux, Next JS, Amazon Web Sevices, DynamoDB, Firebase, Cloud Firestore, Apollo GraphQL, Material UI, HTML, SCSS, and CSS. (03/2019 - Present)

Exploring trending technologies and tools like Next JS, Chakra UI, Styled Components, XState, CSS-In-JS and Interested in contributing to Open-source tools, and Writing blogs.

LANGUAGES

English
Tamil

INTERESTS

Phones | Technology

Blog

Open Source